<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Automated Farming</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Automated Farming</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 12:26:22 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A - Concept Generations</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/03_conceptdev/conceptgen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/03_conceptdev/conceptgen/</guid><description>The team conducted extensive research on existing solutions in the market for both large- and small-scale applications when developing the concept for this project. After spending sufficient time independently researching solutions, the team decided to hold a meeting for a couple of brainstorming sessions during which they employed a variety of brainstorming strategies and concluded the series of brainstorming sessions with a set of concept sketches generated using the C-sketch method, as illustrated below.</description></item><item><title>A - Economical Analysis</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/05_farmbot/econanalysis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/05_farmbot/econanalysis/</guid><description>This section of the report will discuss the economics of purchasing a Farmbot, the ROI period is calculated for multiple scenarios for multiple versions of the Farmbot device. In the beginning the assumptions made for the ROI calculation are discussed. The first table shows the cost to acquire a Farmbot and have it shipped to Kuwait.
Device Device (USD) Shipping (USD) Setup (USD) Total (USD) Total (KWD) Farmbot Express 1495 200 73 1768 535.</description></item><item><title>A - Proof of Concept</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/proof/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/proof/</guid><description>To validate the proposed solution with the limited budget constraint, it was decided to use a 3D printer to replication a Farmbot. The 3D printer was modified to have a webcam attached to it to be used as the weed scanning tool, and the laser to be used in the finalized Farmbot was also attached to the 3D printer to be a part of the prototype.
The figure above shows the exact model used in the fabrication of the prototype and the choice of a 3D printer was obvious as it has a 3 axis gantry system which is exactly what Farmbot uses but this has a much smaller form factor and is widely available and more affordable.</description></item><item><title>B - Bill of material</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/05_farmbot/bom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/05_farmbot/bom/</guid><description>This tables below show the required quantity and the price of each component. It includes the extruisons, plates, brackets, plastic parts, fasteners, hardware, drive train, electronics, wiring, and tubing.
Extrusion: item $/Unit Qty Total Track Extrusion $30.00 4 $120.00 Gantry Column $15.00 2 $30.00 Gantry Main Beam $35.00 1 $35.00 Z-Axis Extrusion $20.00 1 $20.00 Plates and Brackets item $/Unit Qty Total Track End Plate $12.</description></item><item><title>B - New Design</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/newdesign/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/newdesign/</guid><description>Redesigned components for Farmbot As mentioned before Farmbot devices use a universal tool mount that can be attached to a different type of tools to do a certain task. A laser housing was designed using COMSOL to be used in the weed elimination process. To have a better understanding of the designed parts look at the figure below which shows the part from four different dimensions. The final design should be able to be attached to the Farmbot weeder tool using a couple of screws.</description></item><item><title>B - Product Specifications</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/03_conceptdev/prodspecs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/03_conceptdev/prodspecs/</guid><description>Customer Requirements and Importance To make use of the customer, the customer needs previously gathered in the initial market research stage must first be interpreted into semi-technical terms where the team can use to base their design and functionality. After the interpretation of the needs, it is also required to assign an importance rating for each of the interpreted customers' needs to help the team decide what needs they answer in their first iteration or so-called their minimum viable product.</description></item><item><title>C - Bill of Material</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/bom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/bom/</guid><description>The table below lists the equipment and tools used for this project, both the proof of concept and design and fabrication of the laser housing for Farmbot
Item $/Unit Qty Total Creality Laser Engraver 37.99 1 37.99$ Creality Ender 3 Pro 3D Printer 219 1 219$ 1KG Ender PLA Filament 23.29 1 23.29$ Logitech C310 HD WEBCAM 34.</description></item><item><title>C - Functional Decomposition</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/03_conceptdev/functional-decomposition/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/03_conceptdev/functional-decomposition/</guid><description>Watering This diagram illustrates the function decomposition for automatic plant watering. Three system inputs are required: energy in the form of electrical power, water in the form of a fluid, and a command informing the system that it is time to water the plants. The system has two outputs: water to be released on the plants and a signal confirming the plant watering process. When the energy input is accepted as external energy and used to increase the water pressure, the water input is accepted by the system, and the command indicating the plant&amp;rsquo;s needs is accepted, the watering process is initiated.</description></item><item><title>C - Weeder Problem</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/05_farmbot/weederprob/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/05_farmbot/weederprob/</guid><description>As previously stated, the device employs a rotary tool equipped with a 24 [v] DC motor to kill weeds, which may result in undesirable vibration throughout the system. After repeated use, the rotary blades may become damaged, resulting in blade imbalance. Unbalanced blades will generate a series of vibrations that will travel from the motor to the gantry. Vibrations will affect both the tool and the universal mount, dislocating them and potentially affecting their alignment and accuracy.</description></item><item><title>Final Concept Selection</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/04_conceptsel/finalselection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/04_conceptsel/finalselection/</guid><description>After Reviewing multiple concepts and extensive research conducted for the previously mentioned products that are available in the market. The team has selected the Farmbot product as the starting point for their development. This decision was made for various reasons with the primary factor - contributing to this decision-making process - being the fact that in the benchmarking table shown previously the Farmbot concept covers most of the required target specifications discussed in the phase 1 report.</description></item><item><title>Mission Statement</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/02_missionstatement/missionstatement/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/02_missionstatement/missionstatement/</guid><description>The first step in developing any project especially when it is focused and the attempt of solving a real-life problem that can touch the lives of a great deal of people is to have a well-defined well written mission statement and use it to guide the efforts of the team towards the solution. The team went through the process of writing its mission statement in the initial phases and supported it with other information to help better shed the light on what is required and narrow their focus on the exact problem to solve for exactly the targeted user.</description></item></channel></rss>