<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>5- Prototype on Automated Farming</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/</link><description>Recent content in 5- Prototype on Automated Farming</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 12:26:22 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A - Proof of Concept</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/proof/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/proof/</guid><description>To validate the proposed solution with the limited budget constraint, it was decided to use a 3D printer to replication a Farmbot. The 3D printer was modified to have a webcam attached to it to be used as the weed scanning tool, and the laser to be used in the finalized Farmbot was also attached to the 3D printer to be a part of the prototype.
The figure above shows the exact model used in the fabrication of the prototype and the choice of a 3D printer was obvious as it has a 3 axis gantry system which is exactly what Farmbot uses but this has a much smaller form factor and is widely available and more affordable.</description></item><item><title>B - New Design</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/newdesign/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/newdesign/</guid><description>Redesigned components for Farmbot As mentioned before Farmbot devices use a universal tool mount that can be attached to a different type of tools to do a certain task. A laser housing was designed using COMSOL to be used in the weed elimination process. To have a better understanding of the designed parts look at the figure below which shows the part from four different dimensions. The final design should be able to be attached to the Farmbot weeder tool using a couple of screws.</description></item><item><title>C - Bill of Material</title><link>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/bom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 09:40:39 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://me459ku.github.io/Automated-Farming/06_prototype/bom/</guid><description>The table below lists the equipment and tools used for this project, both the proof of concept and design and fabrication of the laser housing for Farmbot
Item $/Unit Qty Total Creality Laser Engraver 37.99 1 37.99$ Creality Ender 3 Pro 3D Printer 219 1 219$ 1KG Ender PLA Filament 23.29 1 23.29$ Logitech C310 HD WEBCAM 34.</description></item></channel></rss>